You don't have to worry, Lulu.
妳不必在意哦 露露
I doubt any of them are dead.
應該是沒有人喪命
After all, you did your very best to persuade the elf.
這都是多虧了妳 拼命地試著說服精靈
But…
可是…
No civilians were involved.
沒有牽連普通人
And the surveillance cameras were also destroyed.
而且監視器也被破壞了
The elders are thorough about these things.
長老派在這方面還是很精明的
I knew our organization was not unified,
雖然我知道我們那組織並不團結
but what were they thinking, sending out those goons to
但他們竟然這麼明目張膽地 來妨礙我們
openly get in our way like that?
那些人到底是想幹什麼
They are afraid of the bug.
他們害怕蟲子
They had a hard time leaving the country and set up headquarters in this remote city in the east.
好不容易才離開這個國家 並在東歐的窮鄉僻壤建立了總部
They fear me leaking information because they did not want to get burned.
所以他們才會害怕我們洩漏情報 而害他們引火燒身
After all, it's impossible to remain uninvolved, so I'll take the flames myself before they take any heat.
畢竟我們無法置身事外 那就在被燒死之前先燒死對方吧
Huh?
什麼
There's a Japanese phrase, "A moth flying into the flames."
日本有句話叫飛蛾撲火吧
As far as the bug is concerned, I believe I'd be the best bait.
我覺得對於蟲子來說 我就是最棒的誘餌
Use me as bait to gather those guys in this city.
以我為誘餌 讓那些傢伙聚集在這座城市
Don't you think that crushing them all in one fell swoop is an effective way?
然後再將其一網打盡 這不也是一種手段嗎
(Dead Mount, Death Play)
《屍體如山的死亡遊戲》
(Episode 22: The Karma)
(#22 The Karma-宿緣-)
There's something I'd like to ask.
我有一件事想問你
What is it?
什麼事
Why were you in the building where the diviner was located?
你為什麼會出現在 那個占卜師所在的大樓裡
Was that giant swarm of arms your trick?
那個巨大的手群是你的戲法嗎
Why do you want to know about that?
你為什麼會對這件事感興趣
Because you may already have attained what you desire.
因為你說不定 已經遇到了你所渴望的東西
Something my employers have been seeking for a hundred years.
也就是我的雇主們找了一百年的東西
Interesting.
有意思
You've already entered the vortex.
你已經身處漩渦之中
No, you're already at the heart of it.
不 應該說你幾乎 已經處於漩渦的中心了
Maybe next time it won't be the puppet.
說不定下次就不是人偶
It'll be your own face that gets blown off.
而是你的項上人頭被擊飛了
Don't! Don't do this to me!
不 不行 我不行了
Pipe down.
你好吵
Sorry, sorry, this is just too funny!
抱歉抱歉 因為這實在太有趣了
I feel bad for you, so I think I'll forgive you for abandoning me.
看在你這麼可憐的份上 我就原諒你拋下我的那件事吧
But I really envy you, Mr. Higuro.
不過我真是羨慕你啊 冰黑先生
SOLITAIRE You've made friends with Solitaire, haven't you?
(雪天鴉) 這就代表你跟雪天鴉變成朋友了吧
Can you get his autograph for me?
不知道你能不能找他要個簽名
And Majiri, I hope she's playing nice with those kids.
萬姬理大姐要是也能 跟那些孩子們和諧相處就好了
So that's the building.
就是那棟大樓吧
I wonder if the kid assassin is in.
那個少年暗殺者不知道在不在家
Do you happen to know?
請問妳知道嗎
You're with the Heilei, right?
妳是黑雷的人 對吧
Excellent timing.
正好
I was just hoping to say hello.
我正想和你們打聲招呼呢
That boy,
小幽
Xiaoyu, is going to become my little brother.
那孩子會成為我弟弟的
So that makes us soon-to-be relatives.
今後我們就是親戚了
FOUND THEM FOUND THEM AGAKURA AGAKURA
(找到了找到了阿牙倉阿牙倉)
So don't be rude.
所以請你們不要再做些不識相的事了
Calling your friends is useless.
就算叫同伴來幫忙也沒有用
I WILL KILL THE DEMON THAT TRIES TO TAKE YOU AWAY FROM ME I'm warning you.
(我會殺死企圖把你從我身邊帶走的惡鬼…) 我奉勸你一句
I see, you're…
原來如此 妳…
HEILEI CADRE, BAO, REAL NAME: LEI YENMEI The only big sister
(黑雷幹部 暴 本名：雷 燕美) 小幽的姐姐
of Xiaoyu is me.
只要有我一個人就夠了
Heilei doesn't need a dirtbag who was knocked down by a little girl from Agakura.
黑雷不需要一個 被阿牙倉的小丫頭給打倒的廢物
I'd happily dispose of him my--
那麼就由我親自來處置…
My daughter is fierce.
我的女兒可是非常殘忍的
When I mentioned making Xiaoyu into a t'ing-fu,
當我說要把小幽做成庭壺的時候
she even tried to kill me, her father.
她甚至還想殺了身為她父親的我
Don't
不要
insult my younger brother, Xiaoyu.
侮辱我的弟弟小幽
So this is revenge for that cute kid assassin?
妳是來為可愛的少年暗殺者報仇的嗎
Not quite.
不完全對
Am I mistaken?
不對嗎
You're right about calling Xiaoyu "Cute."
小幽很可愛 這點沒錯
Yes! That, we can agree on.
正是 確實如此呢
I hate you for maiming my little brother.
我恨妳傷害了我的弟弟
But I also thank you for it.
但我同時也很感謝妳
Thank me?
感謝嗎
After he lost his limbs,
他在失去了四肢後
he was able to get away from that accursed family.
才得以擺脫那個被詛咒的家族
That's unexpected.
真是沒想到呢
I thought the Heilei were much more loyal to their family.
我還以為黑雷的人 很執著於家族傳承呢
I'm not interested in antiquated value systems.
我對陳舊的價值觀不感興趣
But
但是
if you try to take my brother away from me,
如果妳要將我弟弟從我身邊奪走的話
then die.
就去死吧
Are these really a source of magical power?
這真的能成為魔力的來源嗎
Yes, they should replenish the strength of your arms too.
嗯 而且應該還能補充你手臂的力量
So jewels are my fuel…
寶石竟然能當成燃料用…
So that's why Lady Sayo was accumulating so many jewels.
所以小夜大小姐 才會弄來這麼多寶石的碎塊嗎
If raw ore will work, you could buy more of it cheaper, you know?
如果原石也可以的話 那一起買下來就可以更便宜一點
The more transparent and larger it is, the more magic is in it.
透明度越高 單獨的個體越大 其含有的魔力也就越高
So now the only issue is the matter of money.
然後就是錢的問題了
In order to get back the real Polka,
為了奪回真正的波爾卡
I hope to accumulate it as much as possible.
我也希望盡量多準備一些
However, I can't always rely on Mr. Rozan.
不過也不能總是依靠呂算先生
It's my fault.
是我的錯
I was the only one of the guards
護衛裡只有我知道
who knew that stuffed animal was the real Polka.
真正的波爾卡就是那個玩偶
This is not your fault.
這不是你的錯
In any case, we have to report this to Mr. Rozan.
總之 我得把這件事 報告給呂算先生才行
Report to Master…
告訴主公大人…
-It's impossible. -Huh?
-這樣不行 -什麼
Grandpa should have been hospitalized today.
爺爺今天應該已經住院了
Oh! Right, today's…
對喔 今天是…
It's just a routine checkup,
今天是他定期接受檢查的日子
but he'll be under general anesthesia and in no condition for a conversation.
不過他可能因為做了全身麻醉 而不能說話了
Even though it was only for a moment, I was almost relieved.
當時 我有一瞬間感到鬆了一口氣
I thought it would give me the chance to get Polka back safely
在主公大人知道我的過失之前
before Master found out about my blunder.
我想救回波爾卡來挽回自己的過錯
I'm so screwed up.
我真是太差勁了
Do you resent having to protect the real Polka?
因為你並沒有打從心底 想保護真正的波爾卡嗎
-That's none of your-- -Can you really say it's none
-這件事與你… -你能肯定地說這與我無關嗎
of my business given the situation?
在這種情況下
Take it slow.
慢慢來就好
Let's have a little talk.
我們來談一下吧
I disliked him from the beginning.
以前我就看他不順眼
But in all honesty, it's only recently that I've realized I hate him deep down.
但我其實是在不久前 才開始打從心底恨他的
That guy doesn't understand the feelings of Master…
那傢伙不懂主公大人的想法…
I carry these arms and legs I received from Lord Rozan with pride.
我很榮幸能從呂算大人那裡 得到手和腳
And yet he, born Lord Rozan's true son,
那傢伙雖然生為呂算大人的兒子
has no pride in or attachment to his own body.
可他卻對他的身體以及這份血緣關係 沒有任何的驕傲和執著
I will never have any biological connection with Lord Rozan.
這份血緣關係 我是無論如何也無法得到的
I can never be his real son.
我無法成為呂算大人真正的兒子
But that guy…
可是 那傢伙
takes what he has for granted.
卻完全不把這些當作一回事
No, this is my excuse.
不 這是我的藉口
I'm just jealous of him, pure and simple. Forget it.
我只是單純嫉妒他而已 你忘了我說的話吧
I'm so pathetic.
真是悲慘啊
My father
我的父親
sold me for money.
曾為了錢把我賣了
And in the end, he stabbed me for his own greed.
最後他為了自己的慾望而刺死了我
So, I also envy the bonds within families that share the same blood.
所以我也羨慕血親之間的愛
I know that you feel just as bonded as if Mr. Rozan were family.
我能理解你在呂算先生身上 感受到了血親般的愛
And I firmly believe that feeling goes both ways.
但這絕不只是你單方面的情感
I'm sure that, blood aside, your souls are bound.
即便你們沒有血緣關係 但你們一定也有靈魂上的聯繫
So, this connection
所以這份聯繫
should be treasured as well.
也值得你去珍視
Because the pain, if it were severed, would hurt just as deeply.
失去這份聯繫時 不論是哪邊都會感到心痛的
So, this time,
所以這次
I must work to build a world where everyone can live peacefully together.
我一定要創造一個 大家都能平穩生活的世界
Hello, Nezu? What's up?
喂 是根津嗎 怎麼樣了
You already done with your job there?
你那邊的工作都搞定了嗎
So you'll be back here in three days.
你是三天後回來嗎
DINNER, STRATEGY MEETING Just in time.
(晚餐 經營策略會議) 正好
COMPANY PLAN APPROVAL, MANAGEMENT MEETING I have something for you to help me with.
(公司企劃審批會 管理會議) 我有事要你幫我去做
TWO DAYS AGO
(兩天前)
That's about it.
大概就是這樣
I'm sorry for asking you to do this.
抱歉 讓你幫我做這種事
It's fine. Don't sweat it.
沒關係的 你別在意
It's my job to help you with your peaceful life, after all.
畢竟我的工作 就是幫你維持平穩的生活嘛
Polka was kidnapped yesterday.
包括昨天波爾卡被抓走的事在內
As a result, you got involved in something far from peaceful life.
我已經把你牽連進 與平穩相距甚遠的事情裡了
This is for the peace that lies beyond, right?
這不也是為了日後的平穩嗎
Still.
不過 話說回來
STRANGE PHENOMENON SIGHTED IN THE CITY That old man's just going from one stunt to the next.
(市內出現超自然現象) 那個大叔可真是沒完沒了
A WRITTEN CHALLENGE FROM SOLITAIRE What is he thinking?
(來自雪天鴉的挑戰狀) 他到底在想些什麼啊
Huh?
咦
What is that?
那是什麼
SOLITAIRE IS HERE
(雪天鴉 登場)
What do you think he's after?
他這樣做的目的到底是什麼呢
Even asking the guy wouldn't get you any answers.
問那傢伙也沒有用吧
STRANGE PHENOMENON SIGHTED IN THE CITY But the leader
(市內出現超自然現象) 但是 目前係長是
A WRITTEN CHALLENGE FROM SOLITAIRE is a member involved with the Solitaire special investigation HQ.
(來自雪天鴉的挑戰書) 總部的雪天鴉對策中心的一員
If it concerns Solitaire, we need to prioritize the investigation,
哪怕只是在形式上與雪天鴉相關
even if only as a formality.
我們都要優先進行調查
-Rrrgh. -No.
-呃 -不
This isn't the work of Solitaire.
這不是雪天鴉那傢伙做的
A copycat?
你指的是模仿犯嗎
However, this is just my speculation.
不過這只是我的猜測
Simply making something float and then dropping it
讓浮起來的物體掉落下來
is a pretty old trick.
這種戲法已經過氣了
Every aspect of Solitaire's antics carries some significance.
如果是雪天鴉那個傢伙的話 他做事經常是別有深意的
So who exactly did this?
那麼這到底是誰做的呢
Maybe Deus Ex Kinema from Ikebukuro?
是類似於天外救星的其他災厄嗎
Or…
或者…
No.
不
Either way, we've got no shortage of things to look into.
無論如何 我們都不能置之不理
Geez.
真是的
What connects all this stuff that's been going on in Shinjuku?
新宿發生的這些事件之間 到底有什麼樣的聯繫呢
Oh my.
哎呀哎呀
I can't believe an impersonator has emerged.
沒想到竟然會有人模仿我
But I'm not surprised they're doing this.
不過你這麼做也是在情理之中
My spirit of adventure drives me to chase this organization.
對我來說那個組織是一種 值得追尋的浪漫 原來如此
To you, this is nothing more than material for your documentary.
而對於你來說卻是紀錄片的素材
Emperor of Ikebukuro's calamity…
池袋的災厄帝王
Mr. Deus Ex Kinema.
天外救星先生
U-Um…
那 那個…
Excuse me, I'm sorry. You have the wrong person.
對不起對不起 你認錯人了
Who are you?
他們是誰
Hello, I am your fan.
你好 我是你的粉絲
Should I utter a sigh of relief that this wasn't a trap set by the police?
唔 看來這不是警察的陷阱 那我是不是可以安心了
That depends on your attitude.
那要看你的態度才行
Are you saying you're scarier than the police?
你是說你們比警察還要可怕嗎
Sorry, but in our country, it is not customary to carry business cards.
很遺憾 我的母國 並沒有使用名片的習慣
Will you take this as our substitute form of identification?
這個可以代替名片來證明我的身份嗎
The national emblem of the Byandy Empire.
巴亞蒂帝國的國徽
This is the official name of the pattern you've made known to the world.
這就是你向世人公布的 那個花紋的正式名稱
I see.
是嗎
No good. This will take too long.
不行 這樣太花時間了
But when I think of what could happen, this might be…
不過如果為了以防萬一 就多少需要做到這種程度…
Is it true that you summoned your friend's soul?
對了 你真的把你朋友的靈魂 召喚來了嗎
I wouldn't say I summoned him so much as he showed up on his own.
與其說是我召喚來的 不如說是他擅自過來的
So you did have friends where you came from.
你在那邊也有朋友呀
You and Takumi are also friends I hold dear, Misaki.
妳和匠也是我非常重要的朋友
Yeah, you said that before too.
嗯 你之前也是這麼說的
But we didn't meet that long ago, you know?
可我們才剛認識沒多久吧
My master once said,
我師父說過
for us necromancers who live such long lives, bonding with people
對於我們這些長生不老的 死靈術士來說
has nothing to do with the amount of time you've spent with them.
與他人之間的關係是否深厚 跟時間長短無關
Is that how you got chummy with your friend over there so quickly?
你和那邊的朋友也是這樣 很快就成為好朋友了嗎
Yeah, there are often troubles happening over there too.
是啊 那邊也經常有麻煩事發生
You could say he and I were best friends and accomplices.
他既是我的好朋友 也是我的共犯
Accomplices?
共犯嗎
Sorry, I didn't word that right.
抱歉 是我的表達有問題
We just got into mischief together a lot.
我的意思是我們經常一起做些惡作劇
Yeah?
是嗎
I believe the three people who kidnapped
拐走了真正的波爾卡的那三個人
the real Polka have a strong connection to the world over there.
我認為他們跟那邊的世界 也有很深刻的關係
And we've been dragged into the middle of it.
而我們是否已經捲入其中了呢
Or perhaps I'm the one who dragged you into it.
還是說是我主動深入了其中呢
I'm the one who dragged both of you Polka into this to begin with.
一開始是我把波爾卡你們 給牽連進來的哦
It was me who slit Polka's throat.
是我割開了波爾卡的喉嚨
Then I tried to kill the reborn Polka.
然後還打算再次殺掉 重獲新生的波爾卡
I'm the one who pulled you into this world.
也是我把你牽連進 這個世界的麻煩之中的
That's not true…
沒有這回事
Good and bad people will both get involved in your life eventually, you know?
不管是好人還是壞人 終究會把別人牽連進自己的人生中
So,
所以
you can involve all of us in what you think is the right thing.
只要你認為這件事是對的 那就算你把大家牽連進去也沒關係哦
And I am willing to be involved as well.
而且我也願意被你牽連進來
Let's go save the real Polka together.
我們一起去救真正的波爾卡吧
Thank you.
謝謝你
I see.
原來如此
So you guys want to spread the word that you are related to Sabaramond.
你們是想告訴大家 你們才是塞巴拉隆多的親屬嗎
You could say that.
或許是吧
It doesn't matter how.
什麼方式都可以
I can even be a guest in your video.
我也可以作為嘉賓出演你拍的影片
-Yay! -The three of us can also dance together.
-耶 -還是你想要我們三個一起跳舞呢
What?
什麼
A performance by a trio of what I suspect to be aliens.
疑似宇宙人的你們所跳的舞
Interesting.
我還挺感興趣的
Aliens?
什麼宇宙人
Let's not talk about that right now.
先不說這個
You're always on the hunt for paranormal phenomena.
你不是一直都在追求超常現象嗎
Aren't you happy with the current situation?
難道你不該對此刻的狀況感到高興嗎
No, I'm bursting with excitement inside.
不 雖然我心裡十分期待
But I can't make a judgement.
可我無法做出判斷
Judgment?
什麼判斷
Something like this…
這種程度的事情
it can be reproduced with the right materials and sleight of hand.
有可能是通過某種障眼法實現的
Oh…
是嗎
Wait, for real?
喂喂 不是吧
Does he also have a lord elf?
那個人身上也附有精靈大人嗎
Is this the place?
是這裡嗎
The scene of the fire 100 years ago.
一百年前的那個火災現場
So, might there be some clues about Fire-breathing Bug here?
那麼這裡會不會有 關於赴火之蟲的線索呢
The outer facade's been fixed up,
雖然外面修復得很好
but something's off.
但我總感覺有點奇怪
The owner here is a capitalist family from Shinjuku.
這裡的主人是新宿的某個資本家家族
They bought this place for a considerable price after the fire.
火災之後 他們花大錢買下了這裡
Ever since then, their grandchildren have been living elsewhere,
可他們的子孫卻住在了別的地方
and yet they haven't shown any signs of wanting to sell here.
而且好像也不打算把這裡賣掉
Are you sure about this?
可是真的不要緊嗎
This seems pretty unrelated to the Solitaire investigation.
我們現在做的事 已經嚴重偏離雪天鴉的調查了
No.
不
They're getting a little too close to each other lately to call it unrelated.
與其說他們之間沒有關係 不如說最近那些傢伙往來甚密
The calamities are essentially dedicated to their own goals from start to finish.
災厄本質上就是一群 徹頭徹尾地忠實於自身目的的人
Aside from The Grocer, they never got involved with other calamities.
除了雜貨殿之外 他們應該不會跟其他災厄扯上關係
But like with the mark of that Sabaramond organization,
但是對於那個 名為塞巴拉隆多的組織和那個標記
their interests are overlapping too much.
那些傢伙卻不約而同地非常感興趣
You mean Solitaire and Fire-breathing Bug might already be working together?
你是說雪天鴉 已經跟赴火之蟲聯手了嗎
Yes, could be.
是的 很有可能
I strongly agree with your proposal.
我很贊同你的提案
But on one crucial condition.
但我有一個很重要的條件
Interesting, what the condition?
真是有趣 條件是什麼
Um…
嗯
The condition I speak of is
那個條件就是
you have to survive this somehow.
請你們無論如何都要活下來
The years that have passed will be remembered fondly in the heart.
過去的歲月將永遠銘記於心
-The time of departure has arrived. -I was not expecting you to show up so soon.
-離別之時已到 -沒想到他們這麼快就來了
Farewell.
再見了
-Oh no! -Lord Civil!
-糟糕 -西維爾大人
Oh.
哦
So he ruptured the liquid fuel in the air and ignited it.
是讓液體燃料在空中破裂 然後使其著火嗎
It must be a fuel mixture of naphtha and napalm.
該不會是石腦油和凝固汽油的混合燃料
That is, the contents of the napalm bomb and the fuel of the flamethrower.
也就是凝固汽油彈的內容物 和火焰噴射器的燃料
I didn't want it to be this way.
我並不希望是這樣
If so, its high temperature would burn me to death.
如果是的話其產生的高溫 會把我也燒死的
It can't be. Tell me it ain't so.
不是的 對吧 請告訴我不是的
I trust you have some minimal sense of ethics, Fire-breathing Bug.
我一直相信你們至少還有一點 道德底線 赴火之蟲先生
Oh! This is looking really bad!
啊 看來這下糟了
Ha ha! Perfect timing.
哈哈 你們來得正巧
I was just thinking I wanted a chance to test this out.
我正想試一試呢
Is it like… this?
這樣…嗎
Whoa, you gotta be kidding me.
喂喂 不是吧
That's it?
就這種程度嗎
Maybe I have to follow the formal procedure.
不 果然還是得按正式的程序來
Ha ha! I sympathize with bugs like you!
哈哈 我很同情你們這群蟲子
I've already deduced your true identities.
我已經推測出你們的真實身份了
100 years ago, my organization was working on
一百年前我的同伴曾進行過
an experiment to give humans special abilities.
賦予人類特殊能力的實驗
PEEK
(偷偷摸摸)
To keep it secret, they burned all 18 test subjects to death.
他們為了保密 好像把那18名實驗對象全都燒死了
But in the end, only 16 bodies were found.
可最終只發現了16具屍體
That is to say, someone survived.
也就是說有人倖存下來
And multiplied.
並且還繁殖下去了
To carry out your grudge against us.
這都是為了向我們報仇雪恨
I don't know whether it was through science or magic that you did this,
雖然不知道 你們是用了科學還是魔法
you've taken innocent members of the public
不過你們在其他人身上
and planted your thirst for revenge within them.
在無辜的普通人身上 植入了復仇的思想
What a relentless obsession this is.
真是不得了的執念啊
However, in this way, you're doing
不過 這樣一來
the exact same thing the elders did when they robbed 18 people of their lives.
你們的行為跟那些奪走了 18個生命的長老們又有什麼區別呢
Looking at the numbers alone, you're the brutal one.
單從數量上看的話 反而是你們更殘忍吧
You're…right.
你說得…對
Thus,…we are…also sinners.
所以…我們也是…罪人
We are nothing…more than bugs…baked into this world.
我們不過是… 遭到世界焚燒的…蟲子罷了
Once we have burned…you to a crisp,
把你們…燒盡後…
we will vanish…from within these people and…burn ourselves as well.
我們就會…離開他們…並化為灰燼
Nice.
好啊
If that's your intention, then I don't owe you a thing.
既然你們有這個打算 那我這個人也不會感到內疚了
Come, let's crush each other!
來吧 我們互相殘殺吧
Put our respective lives on the line!
賭上各自的生命
What a cheap…threat.
真是廉價的…挑釁啊
A smoke screen? Not gonna work.
障眼法嗎 沒用的
A magic show where the whole crowd disappears?
這是集體消失的魔術表演嗎
What? Did they get away?
啊 讓他們跑了嗎
I see.
原來如此
It seems they won't act recklessly out of revenge.
看來他們似乎並不會 為了復仇而魯莽行事
They must have been testing our combat abilities.
剛才他們應該是在試探我們的戰力吧
It's far better than thoughtlessly flying into the flame like a moth.
看來他們比不加思索 就撲到火裡的蟲子要強多了
What? Ngah?
什麼 啊
This guy might know where those guys' hideout is.
這傢伙說不定知道那些傢伙的老巢
Humph, humph, humph, Lady.
哼哼哼 這位女士
Even if I did know, do I appear to be the type to easily betray friends?
就算我知道 可我看起來像是 那種會輕易背叛朋友的人嗎
-You do.
-像 -像啊
You do.
像呢
Now. Hang on.
好了 請等一下
Then allow me to share some valuable information with you.
那我就告訴你們一個珍貴的情報吧
Information?
什麼情報
The expression "A moth flying into the flame"
飛蛾撲火這個成語
comes from a Chinese Liangshu Text.
出自中國的梁書到溉傳
And doesn't have to do with military strategy or traps,
這個詞的由來 講的並不是戰術或陷阱
-Who cares? -but rather with a story about a grandson outperforming his grandpa.
-誰關心這個 -而是一個老人的孫子比他優秀的故事
That's an interesting story,
雖說我對這事也很感興趣
but I want to hear something else.
但我現在想知道的並不是這個
Why did you go to that building in Shinjuku after getting that symbol?
得到了那個標記的你 為什麼會出現在新宿的那棟大樓裡
What is your connection to the diviner?
你跟那裡的占卜師有什麼關係
Hmph, so you've already reached that conclusion as well, have you?
哼 你心裡不是已經有答案了嗎
True, the moth who flies into the flame is foolish.
撲進火裡的蟲子確實很愚蠢
But if it's a moth who's resistant to fire?
但如果那是耐火的蟲子呢
You!
你這傢伙
MISSED Huh?
(沒打中) 啊
Moreover,
而且
there are some worlds you'll never see unless you fly into the fire.
撲到火裡後說不定還能看到新世界
I'm curious about your powers,
雖然我很在意你們的能力
but I am very busy tonight.
但今晚我很忙
I hope that one day you will show me the incredible world.
希望有一天 你們能讓我見識到不可思議的世界
For that purpose, I'll appear within the flames as many times as it takes.
為此 無論多少次我都願意撲進火裡
Wow.
哇
What?
什麼
Coming to this country was really the right choice.
還好我有來這個國家
The thirst I've had my entire life has been sated a little.
我打從出生就一直感受到的飢渴感 終於得到了一點滋潤
Nothing is making any sense to me.
盡是些莫名其妙的傢伙
Hey, boss. By the way, what was that cannon-like thing you did before?
喂 老大 話說剛才那個 像風之大砲的是什麼啊
That wasn't the power of the Lord Elf, was it?
那並不是精靈大人的力量吧
I tried it out and it worked.
我嘗試了一下就做到了
"It worked," you say.
你怎麼說得這麼輕鬆
So far, I've only been able to use my magic
至今為止我的魔力只能用於
to strengthen my own body and mind.
強化自己的肉體和神經
I was a failure from the start.
我就是個成不了大器的人
Didn't I tell you before coming to this country?
來這個國家之前我就有講過了吧
About my pathetic origins.
關於我那無聊的出身
This body was supposed to have the memories and personality
這具身體的記憶與人格
of a sorcerer from that other world transcribed into it.
都來自那邊世界的一位魔法師
His name was Arius Sabaramond.
他的名字是亞里烏斯塞巴拉隆多
They say the great sorcerer never showed up in this world.
那位偉大的魔法師 最終並沒有出現在這個世界
However, the organization continues to use his name to this day.
可我們的組織卻至今為止 都還在利用這個名字
A product of Sabaramond.
塞巴拉隆多的產物
That's really ridiculous.
真是可笑啊
I was still struggling with that failed magic…
我這個不能使用魔法的廢物
When…
在那時…
Yes, that's what triggered it.
是的 那就是契機
It was the first time I had ever felt
我還是第一次感受到
the magical power within me being manipulated by an outside force.
我體內的魔力被外界所操控的感覺
So I wondered whether I might be able to do the opposite of that sensation.
於是我就在想 我能不能反向利用這種感覺
And, luckily, I managed to do it.
然後就很幸運地做到了
There you go, boasting about your genius.
你又開始自詡天才了
As expected of you, Lord Civil.
真不愧是你 西維爾大人
Well, I'm still only at the threshold.
不過 我目前也只能做到簡單的
Once I get used to the feeling, I'll be able to do more.
如果能習慣這種感覺的話 我就能更加…
I like you and Lulu.
對了 我很喜歡索亞拉和露露你們
You let me feel the world beyond.
是你們讓我感知到了那邊的世界
Don't go saying stuff like that suddenly.
你不要突然說這種話啦
Oh my.
哎呀呀
But this world isn't as chaotic
可惜的是這個世界還沒有混亂到
as I'd like it to be.
可以讓我自由發揮的地步
I have always felt it.
我一直都能感覺到
This isn't where I belong.
這個世界並不是我的容身之處
After all, I was born over there.
畢竟我是在那邊誕生的
I want to go back.
我想回去
To the homeland of my memories that I haven't seen yet.
想回到那個我從未見過 但卻無比眷戀的家鄉
If I can't go back,
如果不能回去
then at least, I wish for something in this world
那我希望這個世界至少也要有
to banish the boredom.
能讓我緩解無聊的事物
Oh, you actually know my phone number.
哎呀 你竟然能知道我的電話號碼
This is my first time speaking to you directly.
這還是我第一次直接跟你對話
Do you want me to make my introduction?
要我打個招呼問候一下嗎
No, no. That won't be necessary.
不用不用 沒有這個必要
After all, you have been a patron
本店在搬店之前
of our store since even before we "moved."
曾多次承蒙您的關照
Does the fact that you're contacting me
你會像這樣直接聯絡我
mean the product is in stock?
說明你已經準備好了吧
The genealogy of Polka Shinoyama.
四乃山波爾卡的家譜
In particular,
特別是他的母親
information about his mother, Kanon Shinoyama.
四乃山卡農相關的情報
(Episode 23: The Declaration)
(#23 The Declaration-宣戰-)